# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 这块羊肉是我伯爷用（猪）腰子换的
Uncle traded some pork kidneys for the lamb
# 现在腰子好多钱一斤哦四伯爷
How much is pork kidney now, uncle?
# 腰子10块一个
10 yuan each
# 10块个20
10 yuan each. For 20 yuan...
# 那就刚好差不多嘎
That's about right
# 差不多 我没吃到亏
Right. Not a bad trade for me
# 头回我换的甲鱼我吃了亏
Last time for the softshell turtle, that was a bad trade
# 这哈我还是晓得哈数（套路）了
Now I know how things work
# 今天我们用这块羊肉煮一个汤
Today, we'll make a soup with the mutton
# 煮一个丸子汤
Make a meatball soup
# 先我们把它切碎
Let's first cut it up
# 切碎了之后剁成肉泥
Then we'll mince it
# 我们这个羊肉最好是用里脊
It's best to use mutton tenderloin
# 然后这个后腿 腿子肉的话
Or the hind leg, the shank...
# 上面有这个筋膜其实也可以
There's some silverskin, which is still fine
# 就是说里脊更好一些
Anyway, tenderloin is better
# 我们这个切刀就不要拿来剁
This knife is a slicer. Let's not chop with it
# 拿这个来剁
Let's chop with this one
# 这个菜应该是你第一次吃
It should be the first time you have this dish
# 也是第一次看到过
And the first you see it
# 而且也是第一次听到说过
Even the first time you ever hear about it
# 你信不信
Believe it or not
# 这个名字叫啥子名字嘛
What's the name of it?
# 就叫做鲜汤
It's literally "the savory soup"
# 这个肉剁好了
The meat is chopped up
# 下一步准备腌这个肉
Next we'll marinate it
# 我们羊肉里面拍一点姜剁碎放进去
Crush and mince some ginger, into the lamb
# 去一下腥
To reduce the smell
# 然后再放一点葱头
Also add some scallion white
# 这个葱现在慢慢的开始老了噶
The scallions are a bit older now?
# 嗯 有点老了
Hmm, a bit old already
# 现在我们加点盐进去调这个味道
Now let's season it with some salt
# 盐可以稍微多那么一点点
We can use a bit more salt
# 再放点胡椒粉
Also some white pepper powder
# 然后我们把它搅拌均匀
Then we stir to mix it up
# 打上劲
Make it sticky
# 我们新鲜的这个羊肉可以不用加料酒
We don't need cooking wine for fresh lamb
# 特别是煮这个汤的时候
Especially when making a soup
# 只需要把它打上劲就可以了
Just need to stir it well, make it sticky
# 我们这个打上劲了之后
After stirring it well
# 再这样子摔一下
Then smash it like this
# 摔好了之后
After smashing
# 我们来处理下一样神秘食材
Let's prepare the next secretive ingredient
# 杀鲫鱼之前我们先准备一些筷子
Before cleaning the "ji yu" carp, we need some chopsticks
# 我今天准备了五条鲫鱼
I got 5 fish for today
# 所以就准备了五双筷子
So there're five pairs of chopsticks
# 我们这个鲫鱼先用筷子
First stick a chopstick into the fish
# 用一双筷子从嘴巴里面插进去
all the way from the mouth
# 这样做就是让它安静一点
This makes it calmer
# 就是不能让它动
Immobilizes it
# 老是动的话不好杀这个鱼
If it moves around, it will be hard to clean
# OK 这样子穿好了
OK, done
# 先放在这里
Put it here
# 它还想越狱
It still attempts to break the jail
# 逮到它 四伯爷
Catch it, uncle
# 好 我们穿第二条
Alright, the next one
# 我们这个穿好了之后
After sticking it
# 可以直接拿着这里来去鳞
We can just grab it and scale it
# 就特别的方便
which is really convenient now
# 这个鱼鳞去掉之后
After removing the scales
# 直接在这个鱼旁边这样子切一刀
Slice at the side of the fish like this
# 切一刀就可以把它放到碗里面
Slice it, and then we can put it in the bowl
# 放到这个盆里了
Put it in the basin
# 待会就直接抠内脏就行了
Later, we can just remove the organs
# 这个我们这个鱼就杀好了
Now we're done cleaning the fish
# 就是去了鱼鳃跟内脏
We've removed the gills and the organs
# 然后简单的改下刀
Then make some slices
# 最后我们再切点姜片
Finally, let's cut some ginger slices
# 然后再挽一点小葱
And tie some scallions
# 可以了 四伯爷
Done, uncle
# 就可以搞了啊
So we can get started?
# 差不多了
Yeah
# 盐巴帮我拿过来一下 四伯爷
Could you take the salt, uncle?
# 你还多撇脱（简单）哦
You made it so easy huh?
# 一下都（可以了）
You finished preparing so fast
# 肯定撇脱噻
Of course, it's easy!
# 现在我们煮之前
Before we start cooking
# 煮汤之间先烧半盆水
Before making the soup, boil some water first
# 把水烧开
Let it boil
# 咱们煮这个鱼汤一定要开水 要热水
We must use hot water to make fish soup
# 制作之前我们先准备半盆清水烧开
Boil half a basin of water before cooking
# 同学们切记煮鱼汤必须用开水
Keep in mind, use hot water to make fish soup
# 否则鱼汤煮不白反而还有鱼腥味
Otherwise, the soup won't become milky white, but smelly instead
# 水烧开之后倒出备用
After the water boils, set it aside
# 锅烧热之后我们加入一些底油滑锅
Heat up the wok, then grease it with some oil
# 煎鱼不滑锅的话鱼皮容易粘锅
If you fry fish without greasing, the skin will stick to the wok
# 热油倒出之后再加入些冷油
Pour out the hot oil, and add some cold oil
# 油温5成热之后锅中加入一些食用盐
When the oil reaches about 150 °C, add in some salt
# 这样可以在煎制的时候鱼不容易烂
So that the fish skin won't break when frying it
# 同时还能去除一定的鱼腥味
And it reduces some fishy smell
# 然后我们再把这个鱼一条一条的放入锅中
Then, we put the fish into the wok one by one
# 学习美食的时候咱们也要先保护好自己
While studying cooking, we also need to protect ourselves well
# 鱼下锅之后先不要动锅
After the fish are all in, don't move the wok immediately
# 慢慢的煎它10秒钟左右
Let them fry for about 10 seconds
# 这样是为了让鱼皮定型
So that we fix the shape of the fish skin
# 10秒钟之后我们再把锅转动起来煎它1分钟
After 10 seconds, we swirl the wok and fry for a minute
# 煎至鱼皮金黄为止
Fry until the skin turns golden yellow
# 同学们家庭小灶则需要2分钟左右
With a homely stove, this takes about 2 minutes
# 煎1分钟之后我们再顺势翻过来煎另一面
1 minute later, flip the fish and fry the other side
# 同样煎它1分钟之后再加入事先准备好的开水下锅
Similarly, fry for a minute. Then add in the hot water
# 大火烧开之后再加入切好的姜片和小葱
Boil it over high heat. Add in ginger slices and scallion
# 然后转中小火煮6分钟
Then turn to medium-low heat and cook for 6 minutes
# 中途咱们也别闲着边煮边去掉浮沫
Meanwhile, we shouldn't be idle. Skim off the scum while cooking
# 6分钟之后鱼汤已经煮成浓白色了
6 minutes later, the fish soup already turns milky white
# 然后再把锅离火
Then move the wok away from the flame
# 将准备好的羊肉挤成丸子下入锅中
Squeeze the lamb into meatballs, and add into the wok
# 丸子全部下入锅中之后开始转小火煮3分钟
After that, simmer for 3 minutes
# 同学们切记丸子下锅之后不能开大火煮
Note that do not boil the meatballs with high heat
# 否则丸子特别容易被冲烂
Otherwise, the meatballs may easily break apart
# 起锅之前我们在碗中撒入适量的葱花
Before serving, put some chopped scallion into the bowl
# 当然了喜欢香菜的同学也可以放
Of course, you can use cilantro if you prefer
# 然后我们把汤里面的小葱捡出来
Then we pick up the scallion from the soup
# 下面开始调味
Next, add seasonings
# 锅中加入少许的食用盐
Add a little salt into the wok
# 然后再加入少许胡椒粉就可以出锅
And add a little white pepper powder. Then it's ready!
# 舀点汤来喝看
Let's try some soup
# 我来给你舀 四伯爷
Let me serve you, uncle
# 吃点羊肉丸嘛
Have some lamb meatballs
# 要的呀
Sure
# 我给你舀一碗
Allow me to serve you
# 羊肉来整的呀这是
Is this lamb?
# 嗯 羊肉丸子
Yeah, lamb meatballs
# 现宰的
Fresh lamb
# 我尝看有盐味没得多
Let me see if it's salty enough
# 盐味肯定是有的
It must be
# 有
Yeah
# 还多鲜这个味道
It's also very savory
# 肯定了
Of course
# 好 可以了可以了
Alright, good
# 安逸
Nice
# 好不好吃嘛
Is it tasty?
# 这次的羊肉是换值了的
This time the lamb was a good trade
# 好吃
Tasty!
# 我们这个汤特别鲜
We made the soup especially savory
# 特别是羊肉加进去了之后
Especially with the lamb in
# 其实你也可以理解成为这个鲫鱼汤加羊肉
Actually, you can also understand it as a "ji yu" carp soup with lamb
# 是吧
Right?
# 为什么叫鲜汤呢
Why do we call it the savory soup?
# 就是因为有鱼有羊
Because there are fish and lamb
(The Chinese character for "savory" consists of "fish" and "lamb" particles)
# 这样鲜汤拿来下面吃肯定安逸哦
If we make a noodle soup with the savory soup, that'll be nice!
# 必须的撒
Definitely
# 它都想吃
It also wanna eat
# 你吃 我都没吃好多点 你吃
You wanna eat? I haven't enjoyed yet, but you wanna eat?
# 我们的狗在旁边馋得不行了已经
Our dog is drooling next to us
# 它想吃
It wanna eat
# 我给你多舀点这个丸子
Let me serve you some more meatballs
# 来 伯爷
Here, uncle
# 这个东西弄来下面可能相当舒服哦吃起
If we make some noodles with it, that should be pretty good
# 伯娘 舀哦
Here, aunt
# 我自己舀
I can help myself
# 要得
Sure
# 你舀来吃嘛
Help yourself
# 要得 你自己舀嘛
Sure, help yourself
# 安逸
Nice
# 好了 大家如果对这个感兴趣的话
Alright. If you are interested
# 一定在家里面试一下
Please try it at home
# 如果买不到羊肉的话
If you can't get lamb
# 可以买那个猪肉也可以啊
You can also use pork instead
# 对不对
Right?
# 羊肉虽然贵
Although lamb is expensive...
# 但是猪肉也不便宜嘎
Pork isn't cheap, either
# 猪肉也没得好相因（便宜）的呀
Pork isn't much cheaper, right?
# 不好意思 打扰了
Sorry, my mistake
# 好了 本期视频就到这里
Alright, that's all for this episode
# 拜拜
Bye bye!
# 再喝一碗
One more bowl